{"test_questions": [[{"question": "If starch containing substrates are used for ethanol production, yeast strain can't be used directly because", "opta": "it doesn't contain amylases to hydrolyze starch", "optb": "starch is not a suitable substrate for the production of ethanol", "optc": "it is converted to pentose sugar", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used to check vortex and to improve aeration efficiency in a fermentor?", "opta": "Impeller", "optb": "Baffles", "optc": "Sparger", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are different substrates used for ethanol production?", "opta": "Starch containing substrate", "optb": "Juices from sugarcane or molasses or sugar beet", "optc": "Waste product from wood or processed wood", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used for aeration in a fermentor?", "opta": "Impeller", "optb": "Baffles", "optc": "Sparger", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ethanol is produced by", "opta": "continuous fermentation", "optb": "batch fermentation", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As the fermentation for the ethanol production is over, the cells are separated to get the biomass of yeast cells that is used", "opta": "for next fermentation", "optb": "as single cell protein for animal feed", "optc": "as manure", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fermentor can be sterilized by", "opta": "keeping it in the oven", "optb": "steam under pressure", "optc": "boiling", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Candida utilis is used for the fermentation of waste sulphate liquor since it ferments", "opta": "hexoses only", "optb": "pentoses only", "optc": "both hexoses and pentoses", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yeast is used in the production of", "opta": "ethyl alcohol", "optb": "acetic acid", "optc": "cheese", "optd": "curd", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "S cerevisiae start producing ethanol with in", "opta": "10 h", "optb": "12 h", "optc": "15 h", "optd": "24 h", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganisms help in the ethanol production?", "opta": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optb": "Zygomonas mobilis", "optc": "Saccharomyces uvarum", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After the fermentation is over, ethanol is recovered by", "opta": "centrifugation", "optb": "distillation", "optc": "filtration", "optd": "cell disintegration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Zygomonas has a merit over yeast because", "opta": "it has more osmotic tolerance to higher sugar concentration", "optb": "it has high tolerance to ethanol", "optc": "it has more specific growth rate", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism is not used in any of the traditional industrial fermentation?", "opta": "E. coli", "optb": "Yeast", "optc": "Bacillus", "optd": "Pseudomonas", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is air supply to the fermentor sterilized?", "opta": "By heat filtration", "optb": "Filtration through fibrous material", "optc": "Filtration through granular material", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the fermentation conditions for the ethanol production?", "opta": "pH 6; temperature 35\u00b0C", "optb": "pH 5; temperature 35\u00b0C", "optc": "pH 6; temperature 30\u00b0C", "optd": "pH 5; temperature 30\u00b0C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used for agitation in a fermentor?", "opta": "Impeller", "optb": "Baffles", "optc": "Sparger", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To maintain aseptic conditions during fermentation which of the following is needed?", "opta": "Sterilization of fermentor", "optb": "Sterilization of air supply", "optc": "Aeration and agitation", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High ethanol concentration", "opta": "promotes yeast growth", "optb": "inhibits yeast growth", "optc": "promotes bacterial growth", "optd": "inhibits bacterial growth", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}